She will die young.
Dia akan mati muda.
Before Lord Habaek comes back and takes the throne,
Sebelum Tuan Habaek kembali dan naik takhta...
she will die.
dia akan mati.
I shall grace you with my blessing,
Aku akan memberimu berkat...
so wake up already.
bangunlah.
You...
Kau…
You now belong to the gods
Kini kau milik dewa.
Accept your fate, or you'll go through everything.
Terimalah takdirmu atau kau akan hidup susah.
How do you feel now?
Bagaimana?
Don't you feel like something in your heart is smacking your head?
Kau tak merasa ada sesuatu di hatimu yang memukul kepalamu?
You should feel honored...
Kau harus merasa terhormat...
to receive the kiss of a god.
karena dicium dewa.
-What are you doing? -You crazy jerk!
- Apa yang kau lakukan? - Dasar berengsek!
I knew it. It didn't wake her.
Sudah kuduga. Itu tidak membangunkannya.
See? I told you she'd be mad.
Lihat? Sudah kubilang, dia akan marah.
Go fix this.
Perbaiki ini.
Are you scared?
Kau takut?
Fine.
Baik.
I'll do it for you just this once.
Akan kulakukan untukmu kali ini saja.
No way.
Tidak.
You've been saying that a lot since you arrived here.
Kau sering mengatakan itu sejak tiba di sini.
Who do you think you are talking to?
Kau pikir kau bicara dengan siapa?
You shouldn't kiss a woman like that out of nowhere.
Jangan mencium wanita tiba-tiba seperti itu.
What are you talking about?
Apa maksudmu?
It didn't wake her. If you go now, she'll slap you in the face.
Itu gagal. Jika Tuan ke sana, dia akan menamparmu.
My gosh.
Astaga.
I must have been out of my mind.
Aku pasti sudah sinting.
I must have gone crazy.
Aku pasti sudah gila!
Why did I close my eyes?
Kenapa aku menutup mataku?
I have to find a logical reason for closing my eyes.
Aku harus cari alasan logis karena menutup mataku.
Right. To avoid trauma...
Benar. Untuk menghindari trauma ...
To avoid trauma,
Untuk menghindari trauma...
I have to find a reason.
aku harus cari alasannya.
Face it and overcome.
Hadapi dan atasi.
Hey, you. Servant.
Hai, kau. Pelayan!
No. Don't do it.
TIdak. Jangan lakukan.
No!
Tidak!
Don't you feel like something in your heart is smacking your head?
Kau tak merasa ada
-Absolutely not. -I'm pretty sure I'm right.
- Tidak ada. - Aku yakin aku benar.
You're wrong.
Kau salah.
Stay away!
Menjauh!
You shouldn't kiss a woman like that out of nowhere.
Jangan mencium wanita tiba-tiba seperti itu.
If you go now, she'll slap you in the face.
Jika Tuan ke sana, dia akan menamparmu.
She must be very stupid to not realize that she was blessed.
Dia pasti sangat bodoh karena tak menyadari bahwa dia diberkati.
I'm hungry.
Aku lapar.
I'm very hungry.
Aku sangat lapar.
I've had enough of stupid servants.
Aku sudah jemu dengan pelayan bodoh.
No, you're wrong about this.
Tidak, kau salah tentang itu.
She'll be awakened and she'll come and find me.
Dia akan terbangun dan dia akan mencariku.
It's nothing.
Bukan apa-apa.
It's because the world has changed.
Karena dunia telah berubah.
Stupid Sang-yu didn't even call me to wake me up.
Sang-yu bodoh bahkan tak membangunkanku.
My stomach...
Perutku…
It's Sunday. You're probably swearing at me, aren't you?
Ini hari Minggu. Kau mungkin mengumpat, bukan?
It's Sunday. You're probably--
- Benar. - Ini hari Minggu. Kau mungkin…
Right, it's Sunday.
Benar, ini hari Minggu.
You're probably back in bed, aren't you? Get up.
Kau mungkin kembali ke ranjang, bukan? Bangun.
-You're in bed again. Get up now. -Enough.
- Kau di ranjang lagi. Bangun sekarang. - Cukup.
Go exercise.
Pergilah berolahraga.
Stop it already.
Hentikan.
Get photosynthesized.
Rasakan fotosintesis. Vitamin D penting bagi wanita.
Strong thighs will help you avoid getting diabetes when you are old.
Paha yang kuat akan menghindari diabetes saat usia tua.
Strong thighs will help you avoid--
Paha yang kuat akan meng...
Dear God! I'd rather kill Yu Sang-yu and go to hell.
Aku lebih suka membunuh Yu Sang-yu dan pergi ke neraka.
Why are there so many humans today?
Kenapa banyak sekali manusia hari ini?
Move. You're blocking my way.
Minggir. Kau menghalangi jalanku.
It's called a bicycle. It's a form of transportation for humans.
Itu disebut sepeda. Itu transportasi untuk manusia.
A cycle? Why are there only two wheels?
Sepeda? Kenapa hanya ada dua roda?
How can they ride it and not fall?
Bagaimana bisa naik dan tak jatuh?
That's because...
Itu karena…
Do you want to see other wheels?
Mau lihat roda lain?
Isn't it so cool?
Keren, bukan?
Not really.
Tidak juga.
Not all things with four wheels are equally fun.
Tidak semua benda dengan empat roda menyenangkan.
Since when does he know how it feels to ride on wheels?
Sejak kapan dia tahu rasanya?
So? What do you want me to do here?
Jadi? Apa yang kau ingin aku lakukan di sini?
There he goes again!
Itu dia!
Nice. My gosh!
Bagus. Astaga.
Awesome. That was great.
Luar biasa. Itu hebat.
Amazing! He even did an ollie.
Luar biasa! Dia bahkan melakukan ollie.
The person who can do all of the four tricks we just showed you
Orang yang bisa lakukan keempat trik yang kami tunjukkan
will unquestionably become the first-place winner.
pasti akan jadi pemenang pertama.
Great.
Bagus.
I should've just stayed home.
Harusnya aku tinggal di rumah.
Why are there so many people here? It's annoying.
Kenapa banyak orang di sini? Ini menjengkelkan.
Best of luck. You got this.
Semoga beruntung. Kau bisa.
You look so cool!
- Kau sangat keren! - Apa itu?
What's going on?
Ada apa?
Here goes the first contestant.
Kontestan pertama.
The blond lady. So far so good.
Wanita rambut pirang. Sejauh ini bagus.
Oh, no! Too bad. She's been disqualified.
Tidak! Sayang sekali. Dia didiskualifikasi.
The second contestant, please proceed.
Kontestan kedua, silakan.
Gosh, that's great! You're doing awesome!
Itu bagus! Kau hebat!
My gosh, he's--
Astaga, dia…
Oh, no.
Tidak.
The third contestant, please come on out.
Kontestan ketiga, ayo keluar.
I think he'll be great.
Kurasa dia akan berhasil.
Oh, my! Amazing!
Astaga. Keren.
Just this once. Please? Just one time.
Sekali ini saja. Kumohon? Sekali saja.
-The fourth contestant... -You want to go back
- Kontestan keempat. - Apa kau mau
-to being a fish again? -I think he'll be good.
- kembali jadi ikan? - Kurasa dia akan baik.
He may be a dark horse.
Dia mungkin kuda hitam.
We don't know how long we might end up having to stay here.
Entah berapa lama kita tinggal di sini.
-Go! -I told you
- Ayo! - Sudah kubilang
that we need money to live here.
kita butuh uang untuk tinggal di sini.
-He didn't make it. -Lord Habaek, please.
- Gagal. - Tuan Habaek, kumohon.
That's too bad. He was so close.
Sayang sekali. Dia nyaris berhasil.
The fifth contestant, please come on out.
Kontestan kelima, keluarlah.
-Please, My Lord. -The fifth contestant?
- Tolong, Tuan. - Kontestan kelima?
Are you giving up?
Apa kau menyerah?
I get it. It must be extremely nerve-racking.
Aku mengerti. Pasti sangat menegangkan.
-Who is it? -Why isn't he coming out?
- Siapa? - Kenapa tak keluar?
Will the one who can do all four tricks come in first place?
Apa yang bisa lakukan keempat trik itu bisa juara?
Be gentle. Please take it easy.
Pelan-pelan saja.
FIRST PLACE PRIZE: 100,000 WON
JUARA 1: 100.000 WON
What must I do if I want to win all three prizes?
Harus apa jika aku ingin semua hadiah?
-Pardon me? -You'll have to give me everything.
- Apa? - Kau harus memberiku semuanya.
Know that this is a huge honor.
Ketahuilah ini kehormatan besar.
-What? -What's he saying?
- Apa? - Apa maksudnya?
-Excuse me, sir. -Goodness.
- Permisi, Pak. - Astaga.
You must be extremely nervous now.
Kau pasti sangat gugup.
You're going the wrong way. You have to come here.
Kau salah jalan. Kau harus kemari.
What?
Apa?
Lord Habaek, please be gentle.
Tuan Habaek, pelan-pelan saja.
Please be careful. Gosh!
Berhati-hatilah. Astaga.
Who is that man?
Siapa dia?
Professional skateboarders can't participate.
Pemain profesional tak bisa ikut.
That man you're looking at now
Pria yang kau lihat itu
had never even seen a skateboard until today.
belum pernah melihat skateboard sampai hari ini.
Don't you...
Kau tak merasa...
feel like something in your heart...
ada sesuatu di hatimu...
is smacking...
yang memukul...
your head?
kepalamu?
You came.
Kau datang.
Yes, he is that guy.
Ya, dia pria itu.
Gosh, this is crazy. Why did I have to run into that guy here?
Astaga, ini gila. Kenapa aku harus bertemu pria itu di sini?
You, my servant over there!
Pelayanku di sana!
I'm here!
Aku di sini!
My gosh, what's his problem? What is he doing?
Astaga, apa masalahnya? Apa yang dia lakukan?
Is he following me? Why? Why is he following me?
Dia mengikutiku? Kenapa dia mengikutiku?
-Are you sure she's a descendant? -Yes.
- Tuan yakin dia keturunannya? - Ya.
What did I tell you? I said it'd wake her up.
Apa kataku? Itu akan membangunkannya.
Hang on a second.
Tunggu sebentar.
-Why on earth am I running away? -Hey, servant!
- Kenapa aku kabur? - Hai, Pelayan!
Oh, right.
Benar.
He said we're all equal to nature. My goodness.
Dia bilang kita semua setara dengan alam. Astaga.
By the way, why is she running away?
Tapi kenapa dia kabur?
She's looking for me, not running away.
Dia mencariku, bukan melarikan diri.
She is running away.
Dia kabur!
Hey, servant!
Hai, Pelayan!
You slow-witted woman! I'm right here!
Dasar wanita lamban! Aku di sini!
Gosh, what a psycho!
Astaga, dasar sakit jiwa.
Let's go.
Ayo.
Goodness, this guy is blocking our way again.
Astaga, orang ini menghalangi kita lagi.
Move!
Minggir!
How impudent.
Kurang ajar.
Gosh, this is so crazy.
Astaga, ini gila.
-Why did I-- -Servant!
- Kenapa aku... - Pelayan!
Why...
Kenapa aku...
Why did I run away when I've done nothing wrong?
lari saat aku tak berbuat salah?
This is all Sang-yu's fault.
Ini semua salah Sang-yu.
Why did he tell me to exercise?
Kenapa dia menyuruhku berolahraga?
I shouldn't have to worry about diabetes. I'm a doctor.
Aku tak perlu cemas diabetes. Aku dokter.
It got in the water. Find something we can use to get it out.
Masuk ke air. Cari sesuatu untuk mengambilnya.
-Gosh, seriously! -I'll come with you.
- Astaga. - Aku bantu.
Please!
Kumohon.
Please save me!
Tolong selamatkan aku.
Dad!
Ayah.
I told you that humans are not trustworthy.
Sudah kubilang manusia tak bisa dipercaya.
You want a prize?
Kau mau hadiah?
Had you wanted to scam me, you should've done it properly.
Jika ingin menipuku, lakukan dengan benar.
Which professional team does he belong to? Seriously.
Dari tim profesional mana dia? Astaga.
Why did you do that?
Kenapa Tuan begitu?
I told you not to go overboard and to do it like a newbie.
Kubilang jangan berlebihan dan lakukan seperti pemula.
You're so mean.
Tuan jahat sekali.
Had I had the kind of power that you have,
Jika aku punya kekuatanmu...
I would have gladly used it for you.
aku akan senang memakainya untukmu.
I feel the same way.
Aku juga.
I wanted to win all the prizes and make you happy.
Aku ingin memenangkan semua hadiah dan membuatmu bahagia.
Lord Habaek.
Tuan Habaek.
My Lord...
Tuanku.
You didn't actually think I'd say such a thing, did you?
Kau tak berpikir aku akan mengatakan itu, 'kan?
Of course not.
Tentu tidak.
It clearly didn't wake her up.
Itu tak membangunkannya.
You should just give up.
Tuan menyerah saja.
It'd be faster to appeal to her sympathy.
Akan lebih cepat menarik simpatinya.
The total site is 20,000 pyeong.
Totalnya 6,61 hektar.
According to our research, there are five landowners in total.
Menurut penelitian kami, ada lima pemilik tanah.
About 15,000 pyeong of the land can be purchased with no issues.
Sekitar 4,95 hektar bisa dibeli tanpa masalah.
Do we have the landowners' contact information?
Punya kontak pemilik tanah?
Yes, we do.
Ya.
Well, but...
Tapi…
Go ahead.
Lanjutkan.
It looks like it won't be easy to purchase the remaining 5,000 pyeong.
Sepertinya tak mudah membeli...
It's because...
Itu karena...
that land belongs to Chairman Shin.
tanah itu milik Ketua Shin.
It's not easy to persuade him.
Tidak mudah membujuknya.
I'll take care of it.
Akan kuurus.
Yes, sir.
Ya, Pak.
Of all, Chairman Shin's land...
Tanah Ketua Shin...
The selling price will jump up.
Harga jualnya akan naik.
Yes, Mr. Choi. Go ahead.
Ya, Tuan Choi. Bicaralah.
Sure. We'll be fine with that.
Tentu. Tak apa.
No. Please prepare the second car.
Tidak. Tolong siapkan mobil kedua.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Apparently, it'll take some time for the windshield wiper to arrive.
Tampaknya butuh waktu untuk pembersih kaca tiba.
Sure.
Baik.
I can’t wait all day.
Aku tak bisa menunggu seharian.
You've kept me waiting since this morning.
Kau membuatku menunggu sejak pagi.
I'm not asking for a new loan.
Aku tak minta pinjaman baru. Hanya perpanjangan.
Is it that hard to check it for me?
Apa sulit untuk memeriksa itu?
What's the point of having a big car?
Apa gunanya punya mobil besar?
My gosh, I'm so sorry.
Astaga, maafkan aku.
I don't think...
Menurutku mereka...
they can afford the repair cost.
tak mampu bayar biaya perbaikan.
Why is it so expensive? It's just a windshield wiper.
Kenapa sangat mahal? Itu hanya pembersih kaca.
What? Rain sensors?
Apa? Sensor hujan?
I get it.
Aku mengerti.
Hello.
Halo.
How was your trip to Gangwon Province?
Bagaimana perjalananmu ke Provinsi Gangwon?
By the way, about the windshield wiper...
Omong-omong, tentang pembersih kaca...
The cost of genuine parts and the labor...
Biaya onderdil asli dan ongkosnya...
I have a friend who works at a body shop.
Aku punya teman yang kerja di bengkel.
-He said if we don't use genuine-- -Do you think they'll understand?
- Katanya jika tak asli... - Pikirmu mereka paham?
I think I'll have to move out.
Kurasa aku harus pindah.
Tell them we'll go through insurance.
- Beri tahukan kita pakai asuransi. - Apa?
Don't be so down when you talk to them.
Ceria saat bicara dengan mereka.
Have confidence and make it simple. Practice.
Percaya dirilah dan buat itu sederhana. Latihan.
Sure. Go through insurance.
Tentu. Periksa asuransi.
All right.
Baiklah.
Patient Ma Bong-yeol is going to be hospitalized today,
Pasien Ma Bong-yeol masuk rumah sakit hari ini.
and he needs a reference from you.
Dia butuh referensimu.
Also, Park Sang-cheol called again.
Park Sang-cheol menelepon lagi.
He said he'll call again.
Katanya akan menelepon lagi.
Gosh.
Astaga.
How can you sleep for that long?
Bagaimana kau bisa tidur selama itu?
I was tired.
Aku lelah.
You might be fine because you're a pure deity,
Tuan mungkin tak apa-apa karena Tuan dewa murni,
but I'm just an ordinary deity, and I get tired like humans.
tapi aku cuma dewa biasa, bisa lelah seperti manusia.
I'm starving too.
Aku juga lapar.
-Is that something I must hear? -Sorry.
- Apa itu hal yang harus kudengar? - Maaf.
Let's go.
Ayo.
Pardon me? To where?
Maaf?
Home?
Rumah?
Where...
Di mana...
BLESSED MENTAL HEALTH
KLINIK JIWA BLESSED
What a coincidence.
Kebetulan sekali.
If I'd have known that you had this in your hand,
Jika aku tahu Tuan simpan itu,
we wouldn't have gone to Gangwon Province and gone through all that.
kita takkan pergi ke Gangwon dan melewati semua itu.
But at least I'm smart enough
Tapi setidaknya aku ingat
to remember the money Ms. Descendant gave me.
uang yang diberikan Nona Keturunan.
Otherwise, we'd be walking all day again.
Jika tidak, kita akan berjalan lagi.
But I wonder whether Ms. Descendant will be so generous.
Tapi aku penasaran apa dia murah hati.
-What? -Hey.
- Apa? - Hai.
-Yes? -I'd like to try driving.
- Ya. - Aku mau coba mengemudi.
-What? -I said I'll do it.
- Apa? - Kubilang aku saja.
-Driving. -What is he saying?
- Mengemudi. - Apa katanya?
-Get out of my car now. -I'm sorry. Okay.
- Keluar dari mobilku. - Maaf.
I'm sorry.
Maaf.
Who came by?
Siapa yang datang?
The agent of the landowner.
Pegawai pemilik tanah.
What did Mr. Bang come here for?
Untuk apa Pak Bang kemari?
I thought they're taking the rent off the deposit.
Kupikir mereka mengambil sewa dari deposit.
It was something like an ultimatum.
Itu semacam ultimatum.
He wants to raise the deposit by 50 million won.
- Dia mau naikkan deposit 50 juta won. - Apa?
That's him.
Itu dia.
Yes. We're almost there.
Ya. Kita hampir sampai.
Yes, sir.
Ya, Pak.
He'd like to see you in an hour.
Dia ingin bertemu satu jam lagi.
Chairman Shin won't look at the business proposal, as you said.
Ketua Shin tidak akan melihat proposal bisnis seperti katamu.
Sure, he won't.
Tentu tidak.
U-TURN 250M AHEAD
PUTAR BALIK 250M DI DEPAN
-I'll help you. -No, thank you.
- Aku bantu. - Tidak, terima kasih.
-It's fine. I can handle myself. Go on. -Okay.
Tak apa-apa. Aku bisa jaga diri. Pergilah.
It says it's across the street.
Tertulis di seberang jalan.
Oh, we have to cross too.
Kita harus menyeberang.
There she is.
Itu dia.
I told you. She has been awakened.
Sudah kubilang. Dia sudah terbangun.
Sir, I'll help you.
Pak, kubantu.
No, it's fine. Go on.
Tidak apa-apa. Pergilah.
Isn't she the windshield doctor?
Bukankah dia dokter itu?
Her hospital must be near here.
Rumah sakitnya pasti di dekat sini.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
I guess she saw something we didn't since she's a psychiatrist.
Kurasa dia lihat hal yang tak kita lihat karena dia psikiater.
Maybe.
Mungkin.
She looks good in the doctor's gown.
Dia cantik memakai jas dokter.
I agree.
Aku setuju.
My goodness!
Astaga.
How did you get here?
Bagaimana kau bisa kemari?
I took what's called a taxi.
Aku naik yang disebut taksi.
It was more spacious than your car.
Lebih luas dari mobilmu.
So now I only have half of the money you gave me.
Kini hanya ada separuh uang yang kau berikan padaku.
Good to see you again.
Senang bertemu lagi.
Why did you just leave yesterday?
Kenapa kau pergi kemarin?
What?
Apa?
If you've been awakened, you should come and say hello.
Jika kau sadar, kau datang dan menyapa.
Teach her etiquette first.
Ajari dia sopan santun.
I won't need your help so much.
Aku tak butuh banyak bantuan.
First, I need a house to stay,
Pertama, tempat tinggal,
and since I don't eat, food for Namsuri to feel full,
dan karena aku tak makan, makanan untuk Namsuri
and a change of clothes.
hingga kenyang dan baju ganti.
Give me what you call "money."
Berikan yang kau sebut uang.
I heard it's better if you have more.
Kudengar lebih baik jika punya banyak.
I'll let you know if I need anything else.
Kuberi tahu jika butuh yang lain.
Also, there are gods I have to find.
Juga, ada dewa yang harus kutemukan.
The coronation must take place immediately.
Penobatan harus dilakukan segera.
So try your best to find them as fast as you can.
Cobalah cari secepat mungkin.
Do you have any questions?
Ada pertanyaan?
Let's talk.
Ayo bicara.
Sir, you shouldn't let him do what he wants.
Pak, jangan biarkan dia lakukan keinginannya.
Does he go to a hospital?
Apa dia ke rumah sakit?
Pardon?
Apa?
No?
Tidak?
Hey, look.
Hai, dengar.
Mental illness is the same as physical illness.
Penyakit mental sama dengan penyakit fisik.
Don't you go to a hospital when you're sick?
Kau tak ke rumah sakit saat sakit?
Do you just endure the pain of your injuries until it gets better?
Kau menahan sakit sampai lukamu membaik?
Namsuri is very hungry.
Namsuri sangat lapar.
And I need water.
Aku butuh air.
Then go home and take care of your problems.
Kalau begitu pulanglah dan atasi masalahmu.
-Where is your house? -No.
- Di mana rumahmu? - Tidak.
Not my house. Your house.
Bukan. Rumahmu.
Sorry, but we don't have a place to go.
Maaf, kami tak punya tempat tujuan.
Please help us.
Bantu kami.
Then you could go to the community service center
Kau bisa ke pusat layanan masyarakat
in your neighborhood and ask for help.
di lingkunganmu dan minta bantuan.
I don't know how good the welfare system is in this country,
Aku tak tahu baiknya sistem kesejahteraan di negara ini...
but I think it is the country's duty
tapi kurasa tugas negara
to take care of and be responsible for people like you.
mengurus dan bertanggung jawab atas orang sepertimu.
It's not a personal problem.
Bukan masalah pribadi.
Let's eat up.
Ayo makan.
That's why we're paying taxes.
Itu sebabnya kita membayar pajak.
I can't afford to look after other people.
Aku tak mampu merawat orang lain.
Then why did you just walk with the old man?
Lalu kenapa kau berjalan dengan pria tua itu?
When...
Kapan aku melakukannya?
I saw it. I saw it all.
Aku melihatnya. Aku melihat semuanya.
-I was just walking. -You were walking with him.
- Aku hanya berjalan. - Di sampingnya.
I was only walking.
Aku hanya berjalan.
You're not very honest.
Kau tak jujur.
That's got nothing to do with this. The country--
Tak ada hubungannya dengan ini. Negara ini...
-I don't know what you're talking about. -I know.
Aku tak tahu maksudmu.
Anyway, if you ever show up here again,
Jika kalian muncul di sini lagi, aku akan melaporkanmu ke polisi.
If you leave like this, I'll let you go.
Jika kau pergi, aku akan melepasmu.
That means I'll abandon you.
Aku akan meninggalkanmu.
I'm very glad to hear that.
Aku senang mendengarnya.
See?
Lihat?
It did not wake her.
Dia tak terbangun.
-What's up? -Did you meet Mr. Bang?
- Apa? - Sudah bertemu Tuan Bang?
No, not yet. Where's his office again? I should go there.
Belum. Di mana kantornya? Sebaiknya kita ke sana.
It's not far, but you should get back here first.
Tidak jauh, tapi kau harus kembali ke sini dulu.
Mr. Ma Bong-yeol's guardian is here.
Wali Pak Ma Bong-yeol ada di sini.
He's checking into a hospital today, and he needs your signature.
Dia masuk RS hari ini dan butuh tanda tanganmu.
Really? Okay, I'll be there shortly.
Sungguh? Aku segera ke sana.
You're in trouble. Do you know who he is?
Kau dalam masalah. Kau kenal dia?
-What? -Sorry?
- Apa? - Maaf?
-What did you just say? -I didn't say anything.
- Apa katamu? - Aku tak bilang apa-apa.
You'll suffer to death.
Kau akan menderita sampai mati.
Gosh, these people...
Astaga, mereka...
How dare you threaten me?
beraninya mengancamku?
Now we won't even be able to appeal to her sympathy.
Kini kita tak bisa menarik simpatinya.
I asked you to give me a heads-up before you do anything.
Kubilang beri tahu aku sebelum Tuan bertindak.
We should take care of urgent business first.
Kita selesaikan urusan mendesak dulu.
I hate that we have to do this,
Aku benci ini...
but we should go there.
tapi kita harus ke sana.
Where?
Ke mana?
The place I buried gold.
Tempatku mengubur emas.
-Gold? -I buried some gold
- Emas? - Aku mengubur emas
when I came here 55 years ago.
saat kemari 55 hari lalu.
I didn't do it to prepare for a day like this.
Aku tak persiapkan untuk hal ini.
I didn't know it'd be this useful.
Aku tak tahu akan berguna.
With that gold, I'll be able to find a better place for you to stay.
Dengan itu, aku bisa menemukan tempat yang lebih baik untukmu.
So...
Maksudmu...
you're saying that you made me go through all this trouble
kau membuatku melalui semua ini
when we had that option?
padahal kita punya pilihan itu.
I didn't want to go there because it has bad vibes.
Aku tak mau ke sana karena nuansanya buruk.
Fugitives from the divine world gather there.
- Buronan alam suci berkumpul di sana. - Di mana?
-The pear tree field. -Pear tree field?
Ladang pohon pir.
This used to be a field of pear trees.
Dulu ini adalah ladang pohon pir.
Gosh, this is not what I expected.
Ini tak sesuai dugaanku.
You say that all the time.
Kau selalu mengatakan itu.
-Goodness. -I'm sorry.
- Astaga. - Maaf.
Just deal with it.
Tahan saja.
Here. Is that enough?
Ini. Apa itu cukup?
You're one strange man.
Anda orang yang aneh.
Are you really going to eat all this food?
Kau sungguh mau makan semua ini?
Hold on. You need to finish the job before you start eating.
Tunggu. Selesaikan pekerjaan sebelum mulai makan.
What?
Apa?
Oh, right.
Benar.
The blockage on the path from east to west will be removed,
Sumbatan di jalan dari timur ke barat akan dihapus
which means energy will rush in from both directions.
yang berarti energi akan masuk dari dua arah.
Like a tiger that threatens all other creatures,
Seperti harimau yang mengancam semua makhluk lain,
you have a triumphant and bright future ahead.
masa depanmu akan cerah dan cemerlang.
You can expect great news around November this year.
Ada kabar baik sekitar bulan November tahun ini.
Great news?
Kabar baik?
Eat up.
Makanlah.
What does hunger feel like?
Bagaimana rasanya lapar?
Well, I can't really describe it in words,
Aku tak bisa menggambarkannya dengan kata-kata,
but it sort of makes you act servile.
tapi itu membuatmu jadi budak.
How pathetic.
Menyedihkan.
It's just a feeling.
Itu hanya perasaan.
You're right. By the way, I think what you said is right.
Tuan benar. Omong-omong, ucapanmu benar.
You said losing your power doesn't mean you're no longer a god.
Kehilangan kekuatan bukan berarti Tuan bukan dewa.
Since you still don't feel hunger,
Karena Tuan masih belum merasa lapar,
you must be right.
Tuan pasti benar.
Did you just realize that now?
Kau baru sadar?
Let's go.
Ayo.
Pardon? May I finish eating this?
Boleh aku selesaikan makan?
What should we do now?
Kita harus bagaimana?
It'd be best if we could find those deities,
Bagus jika kita temukan para dewa itu,
but we have no means to do so right now.
tapi kita tak tahu caranya.
Even if we decide to wait for your power to come back,
Walau kita menunggu kekuatanmu kembali,
we can't keep staying there.
kita tak bisa tinggal di sana.
Plus, I'll continue to get hungry,
Ditambah, aku akan lapar,
so we'll need to find a way to sustain ourselves.
jadi, kita harus cari cara bertahan.
You're still Lord Habaek even without your power,
Kau masih Tuan Habaek walau tanpa kekuatan,
but this is really inconvenient.
tapi ini sangat tak nyaman.
Why do you think you lost your power?
Menurutmu kenapa kekuatanmu hilang?
We should find Ms. Descendant again and ask her for--
Kita harus mencari Nona Keturunan dan memintanya...
You're being such a nuisance. I can't take this anymore.
Kau mengganggu. Aku tak tahan lagi.
Pardon?
Apa?
What did I do?
Apa yang kulakukan?
Stop following me and reveal yourself already.
Berhenti mengikutiku, keluarlah.
Why are you following me?
Kenapa mengikutiku?
Aren't you Lord Habaek?
Bukankah kau Tuan Habaek?
Who are you?
Siapa kau?
It's me.
Ini aku.
He does look familiar.
Dia terlihat tak asing.
It's me, Jugeollin.
Ini aku, Jugeollin.
Don't you recognize me?
Tak mengenaliku?
-I don't know you. -Jugeollin?
- Tak kenal. - Jugeollin?
There's no way you don't know me.
Tak mungkin kau tak mengenalku.
You better know me.
Sebaiknya kau kenal.
-You-- -You little...
- Kau... - Kau…
What on earth was that about?
Apa-apaan itu?
You must've really lost all of your power.
Kau pasti kehilangan semua kekuatanmu.
How...
Bagaimana bisa kau tak mengenalku?
-Who are you? -I...
- Siapa kau? - Aku...
I've been desperately waiting for a day like this. You...
Aku sudah lama menunggu hari seperti ini.
You're doomed now.
Kini tamatlah riwayatmu.
Who is that scum?
Siapa bajingan itu?
Lord Habaek.
Tuan Habaek.
Are you all right?
Tuan baik-baik saja?
Who is he?
Siapa dia?
He's the voracious deity, Jugeollin.
Dia dewa rakus, Jugeollin.
He fled from the Land of Water because of you and Mura.
Dia kabur karena Tuan dan Mura.
Who?
Siapa?
He kissed you.
Dia menciummu.
You'll be okay, right?
Tuan akan baik-baik saja, 'kan?
Yes, Mr. Bang.
Ya, Pak Bang.
I'm one of your tenants at Daebak Building.
Aku salah satu penyewa di Gedung Daebak.
Blessed Mental Health Clinic.
Klinik Jiwa Blessed.
Yes, that's right. Where are you now?
Ya, benar. Di mana kau sekarang?
I'd like to meet with you.
Aku ingin menemuimu.
Look who's here.
Lihat siapa ini.
Where do you even come from?
Sebenarnya kau berasal dari mana?
What brings you here?
Kenapa kau kemari?
Are you here to take more things from my family or what?
Mau mengambil lebih banyak barang dari keluargaku?
-He's completely ignoring me. -Hello, sir.
- Dia mengabaikanku. - Halo, Pak.
-Hey, my nephew is here. -He's not really your nephew.
Hai, keponakanku ada di sini.
Just because he's our family on paper doesn't make him our family.
Hanya karena dia keluarga di atas kertas tak menjadikannya keluarga.
Be respectful, will you?
Tunjukkan sedikit hormat, mengerti?
Respectful, my foot.
Hormat apanya?
Be quiet. Give me the car key.
Diam. Berikan kuncinya.
Grandpa!
Kakek.
You know how well people treat you because you own a few buildings.
Orang memperlakukanmu dengan baik karena kau pemilik sedikit gedung.
Let me run my own talent agency.
Biar aku jalankan agensi bakatku sendiri.
Your car is over there, so just leave.
Mobilmu di sana, pergilah.
From the towing fee and the storage cost to the penalty...
Dari biaya derek, biaya penyimpanan, dan penalti...
You eat up so much money.
Kau menghabiskan banyak uang.
Grandpa, listen to me.
Kakek, dengarkan aku.
A celebrity like me shouldn't get a ticket for illegal parking
Selebritas sepertiku tak bisa ditilang karena parkir liar
Help me start a business!
Bantu aku memulai bisnis!
Let's go.
Ayo.
Don't stay out late!
Jangan pulang larut!
Grandpa, please. Grandpa!
Kakek, kumohon. Kakek!
Don't leave, Grandpa.
Jangan pergi, Kakek!
Mr. Cha.
Pak Cha.
Why did you give my role in the romantic drama to a no-name actress?
Kenapa kau beri peranku dalam drama romantis kepada artis tanpa nama?
Sir!
Pak!
Hello.
Halo.
-Is the tenant leaving today? -Yes.
- Apakah penyewa pergi hari ini? - Ya.
Do a thorough check before they leave.
Periksa menyeluruh sebelum mereka pergi.
Make sure they don't leave any garbage in the property.
Pastikan mereka tak meninggalkan sampah.
You know how expensive garbage bags are.
Kau tahu kantong sampah itu mahal.
Please don't worry, sir.
Jangan khawatir, Tuan.
That rude jerk.
Dasar kurang ajar.
He didn't even bother to say goodbye.
Dia bahkan tak berpamitan.
Eighth floor.
Lantai delapan.
I paid so much money for her medical school.
Aku membayar banyak uang untuk sekolah kedokterannya.
If I had two grandchildren, I would've gotten rid of her already.
Jika aku punya dua anak, aku akan menyingkirkannya.
You won't believe how much I had to pay in taxes this month.
Kau tak akan percaya jumlah pajakku bulan ini.
Those ruthless thieves.
Para pencuri kejam itu.
They've done nothing for me, but why are they taking so much money?
Mereka tak melakukan apa pun untukku, kenapa ambil banyak uang?
So,
Jadi...
did you say that you're going to build a new resort?
apa kau bilang akan membangun resor baru?
Yes, sir. I think I'll need a lot of your help.
Ya, Pak. Kurasa aku butuh banyak bantuanmu.
I'm just an old man. How will I be able to help you?
Aku hanya pria tua. Bagaimana aku bisa membantumu?
I vaguely heard about it from Mr. Min.
Aku mendengarnya sedikit dari Pak Min.
But it was so complicated that I really couldn't understand.
Tapi itu sangat rumit, aku tak paham.
So let's just get to the point.
Langsung saja.
How much will I be able to earn from this deal?
Berapa yang bisa kuhasilkan dari bisnis itu?
I'm planning to pay five times the official price.
Aku mau membayar lima kali lipat dari harga resmi.
Those countrymen will get to earn some money.
Orang-orang desa itu akan dapat uang.
How much will you give me then?
Berapa yang akan kau berikan kepadaku?
That's so immoral.
Sungguh tak bermoral.
"Immoral"?
Tak bermoral?
You can't even afford to pay rent, so I'm taking the money from your deposit.
Kau bahkan tak bisa bayar sewa, jadi, kuambil depositmu.
Don't you think you're the one who's being more immoral?
Apa kau tak berpikir kau yang lebih tak bermoral?
I'm really sorry about that, and I'm also very grateful.
Aku sangat menyesal tentang itu dan aku juga sangat berterima kasih.
So please help me by convincing him not to raise the deposit.
Jadi tolong bantu aku meyakinkan dia agar tak menaikkan depositnya.
Once my clinic settles down--
Setelah klinikku baik...
"That's exactly what I don't understand!
"Itulah yang tak kumengerti!
Why are you trying to settle down in my building?"
Kenapa kau mencoba menetap di gedungku? "
That's exactly what the chairman will say,
Itu persis yang akan dikatakan ketua
in my opinion.
menurut pendapatku.
"She should settle down in some other building!
"Dia harus menetap di gedung lain!
Why is she trying to settle down in my building?"
Kenapa dia berusaha menetap di gedungku? "
That's what he'll say as he scolds me.
Itu yang akan dia katakan saat dia menegurku.
Okay, then. I'll talk to him myself.
Baiklah. Aku akan bicara dengannya.
No, you can't do that!
Kau tak boleh melakukannya!
The chairman is not available right now.
Ketua tidak ada sekarang.
I'll pay six times the original price for your land.
Kubayar enam kali harga asli tanahmu.
You're paying five times the original price to those
Kau membayar lima kali lipat harga asli untuk mereka
who you're not even acquainted with.
yang tak kau kenal.
Don't you think you're being cheap towards your family?
Apa kau tak terlalu murah pada keluargamu?
I won't be too greedy.
Jangan rakus.
Just pay me... ten times the original price.
Bayar saja 10 kali...
I'm sure you have your reputation to think about at work,
Kau harus pikirkan reputasimu di kantor,
so I, your uncle, will help you save face.
pamanmu ini akan membantumu menjaganya.
By the way, are you trying to build an amusement park or something?
Omong-omong, apa kau ingin membangun taman bermain?
I heard restaurants earn a lot of money in amusement parks.
Restoran menghasilkan banyak uang di taman hiburan.
It'll be open bidding.
Ini penawaran terbuka.
If you're interested, you should get ready to participate.
Jika tertarik, silakan berpartisipasi.
Why are you making things so complicated?
Kenapa kau membuatnya rumit?
You can just add another article in my contract.
Kau bisa menambahkan pasal lain di kontrakku.
I'm willing to give you my precious land.
Aku memberimu tanahku yang berharga. Buatlah jadi mudah bagiku.
I can't do that, sir.
Aku tak bisa melakukannya, Pak.
Who is it?
Siapa itu?
Who are you?
Siapa kau?
The third floor...
Lantai tiga...
What?
Apa?
I'm a tenant on the third floor of Daebak Building.
Aku penyewa di lantai tiga Gedung Daebak.
I'm a doctor working at Blessed Mental Health.
Aku dokter Klinik Jiwa Blessed.
Oh, yes. That mental hospital.
Ya. Rumah sakit jiwa itu.
It's not exactly a mental hospital.
Bukan rumah sakit jiwa.
You suddenly doubled the deposit, so I came here to talk about that.
Kau tiba-tiba gandakan depositnya, aku mau bicarakan itu.
That's great. I've been meaning to meet you anyway. I'm glad you came.
Itu bagus. Aku ingin menemuimu. Aku senang kau datang.
Why are you always so late in paying your monthly rent?
Kenapa kau selalu telat bayar sewa bulananmu?
You have no common sense.
Kau tak punya akal sehat. Kau harusnya paham.
Why are you causing a huge loss on someone else's property?
Kenapa kau menyebabkan kerugian besar pada properti orang lain?
I barely manage to live day to day with your monthly rent.
Aku tak bisa hidup dari hari ke hari dengan sewa bulananmu.
Are you trying to starve me to death?
Kau mau kami mati kelaparan?
You have a guest with you, so I'll just come back next time.
Kau punya tamu, aku akan kembali lain kali.
There's no need.
Tidak perlu.
You can stay if you have money. If not, please move out.
Tinggallah jika punya uang atau keluar.
I'm not so smart, so I hate complicated things.
Aku tak begitu pintar, jadi, aku benci hal rumit.
Young people these days only seem to blame others.
Anak muda belakangan ini hanya menyalahkan orang lain.
My gosh, why did he have to be there again?
Astaga, kenapa dia harus di sana lagi?
You now belong to the gods.
Sekarang kau milik dewa.
Accept your fate, or you'll go through everything.
Terimalah takdirmu atau kau akan celaka.
This can't be...
Ini bukan...
the "everything" that I'll be going through, can it?
maksudnya celaka bagiku, bukan?
Why am I thinking of such weird things?
Kenapa aku pikirkan hal aneh seperti itu?
Please give me water. I'm really thirsty.
Tolong beri aku air. Aku sangat haus.
Can't you hear me? Please give me water.
Kau dengar aku? Tolong beri aku air.
Are you trying to make me go dry?
Kau mau aku kering?
My gosh.
Astaga.
Why did she have to be in my way? How stupid.
Kenapa dia harus menghalangiku? Bodoh sekali.
I'm sorry.
Maaf.
Doors closing. Basement one.
Pintu ditutup. Basemen satu.
First floor. Doors opening.
Lantai satu. Pintu terbuka.
You should go back to the bank again and ask them for a loan.
Kembalilah ke bank dan minta pinjaman.
Why are you always so nosy? You should mind your own business.
Kenapa kau selalu ikut campur?
You don't seem to mind your own business either.
Kau juga tak urus urusanmu sendiri.
-What did you say? -I saw you
- Apa katamu? - Aku melihatmu
putting on a very awkward act at the crosswalk earlier.
melakukan aksi canggung di penyeberangan tadi.
-I was just walking. -You were walking with him.
- Aku hanya berjalan. - Di sampingnya.
-You're not very honest.
- Kau tak jujur.
What is their problem?
Apa masalah mereka?
-I wasn't criticizing you. -I didn't say you were.
- Aku tidak mengkritikmu. - Aku tak bilang begitu.
-About that windshield wiper-- -I'll handle it
- Pembersih kaca... - Akan kuurus dengan asuransi.
I was just about to tell you that you don't need to pay for it.
Aku baru akan memberitahumu bahwa kau tak perlu membayarnya.
Should I just mind my own business?
Urus urusanku sendiri?
Well...
Itu...
Yes, that's right.
Itu benar.
I see.
Aku mengerti.
Then I'd like you to pay the price.
Aku ingin kau membayarnya.
Are you the guardian of Ma Bong-yeol?
Apa kau wali Ma Bong-yeol?
What? He ran away?
Apa? Dia kabur?
You're not very honest.
Kau tak jujur.
Why do you care?
Kenapa kau peduli?
What?
Apa?
-What? -He ran away
- Apa? - Dia melarikan diri
because he suddenly had a change of heart.
karena berubah pikiran.
Why did you let him get away?
Kenapa kau biarkan dia kabur?
What?
Apa?
Why would I look for him?
Aku harus mencarinya?
I'm not in good condition either.
Aku juga sedang tidak baik.
I keep hearing weird things. I should get some rest.
Aku terus mendengar hal aneh. Aku harus istirahat.
It has nothing to do with our hospital anymore.
Tak ada hubungannya dengan klinik kita.
They'll take care of it now.
Mereka akan mengurusnya.
Forget that and call the police.
Lupakan itu dan hubungi polisi.
Ask them if there's any progress in catching the thief.
Tanyakan apakah ada kabar pencuri itu.
Are you looking at what that kid's eating right now?
Apa Tuan lihat makanan anak itu sekarang?
-No. -Then what are you looking at?
- Tidak. - Lalu apa yang kau lihat?
I'm not looking at anything.
Tidak ada.
Do you want some?
Tuan mau?
Take that away.
Singkirkan itu.
Please let me know if you feel dizzy,
Beri tahu jika Tuan merasa pusing,
have back pains, or feel weak.
sakit punggung, atau lemah.
That's how it feels when you're hungry.
Begitulah rasanya saat lapar.
Eating this will help you feel better.
Makan ini, Tuan akan merasa baikan.
I guess if you lose your power, spells of the lower deities work on you.
Kekuatanmu hilang membuatmu seperti dewa biasa.
Why aren't we using a taxi?
Kenapa tak pakai taksi?
We need to save up. We both need to eat to survive now.
Kita harus menabung. Kini kita harus makan untuk bertahan hidup.
I had no idea Jugeollin would be here.
Aku tak tahu Jugeollin di sini.
When exactly was it
Kapan dia menantangmu dan meninggalkan bekas luka...
He didn't leave that scar.
Dia tak meninggalkan luka.
He accidentally dropped his knife as he was so nervous.
Dia tak sengaja jatuhkan pisaunya.
As his knife dropped, it hit a twig which bounced back and--
Saat itu jatuh, kena ranting dan memantul ke...
It doesn't matter.
Tidak masalah.
I heard he ran away after Mura threatened to kill him.
Kudengar dia kabur setelah Mura mengancam akan membunuhnya.
But I didn't know he'd be here.
Ternyata dia di sini.
I didn't know the human world would be so full of trash.
Aku tak tahu dunia manusia penuh dengan sampah.
Why do you think Jugeollin asked you to fight him?
Kenapa Jugeollin memintamu melawannya?
He must've been out of his mind.
Dia pasti sudah gila.
This is not good.
Ini tak bagus.
You're even going to feel hunger now.
Kini Tuan merasa lapar.
Why are things getting so complicated?
Kenapa ini jadi rumit?
INCOMING CALL: SEUL-KI
PANGGILAN MASUK SEUL-KI
Hey, I'm almost there.
Hai, aku hampir tiba.
I'm getting off now. Okay.
Aku akan turun sekarang. Baiklah.
Mura?
Mura?
-Lord Habaek! -Doors closing.
- Tuan Habaek! - Pintu ditutup.
Lord Habaek!
Tuan Habaek!
-Lord Habaek! -Namsuri.
- Tuan! - Namsuri.
Lord Habaek!
Tuan Habaek!
Oh, no. What am I going to do?
Tidak. Aku harus bagaimana?
He apparently found a way to contact aliens.
Dia menemukan cara menghubungi alien.
He uploaded a selfie on his social media account.
Dia unggah swafoto di akun medsosnya.
Hey, you're not supposed to look into a patient's private life.
Kau tak seharusnya tahu kehidupan pribadi pasien.
I didn't have a choice because he threatened that
Aku tak punya pilihan karena dia mengancam
he'd go to another hospital if I didn't add him.
ke klinik lain jika tak mengikutinya.
I think he's at a subway station right now.
Dia di stasiun kereta bawah tanah.
It looks like he's in Gangseo-gu by looking at the background.
Sepertinya di Gangseo-gu, dari latar belakangnya.
Gosh, I feel like I know this place.
Rasanya aku tahu tempat ini.
It says the next stop is Seonyudo Park.
Stasiun berikutnya adalah Taman Seonyudo.
That means he's near the Han River.
Berarti di dekat Sungai Han.
What a great detective you are.
Kau detektif hebat.
But what's this?
Tapi apa ini?
He wrote that he has finally met a god.
Dia menulis akhirnya bertemu dewa.
I'm so sick of this nonsense about gods.
Aku muak dengan omong kosong tentang dewa.
I'm the one who wants to meet a god.
Akulah yang ingin bertemu dewa.
My mother told me that humans need to eat rice to gain energy.
Ibuku bilang manusia butuh makan nasi untuk mendapat energi.
But I gained energy by eating chicken and pizza.
Tapi aku dapat energi dengan makan ayam dan piza.
Of course, that's only after my mother passed away.
Tentu saja, itu setelah ibuku meninggal.
Here.
Ini.
Please eat this.
Makan ini.
Don't refuse and eat up.
Jangan menolak, makanlah.
The eldest should always get the drumstick.
Anak tertua selalu dapat paha.
-Here. -What are you doing?
- Ini. - Apa yang kau lakukan?
Gosh, I'm sorry.
Aduh, maaf.
People will believe me now that I have a photo to show them as evidence.
Orang-orang akan percaya karena aku punya foto sebagai bukti.
Oh, right. How's TF 1004 doing?
Benar. Bagaimana keadaan TF 1004?
I haven't been able to meet Obama yet.
Aku belum bisa bertemu Obama.
I'm doing my best.
Aku melakukan yang terbaik.
But I'm sorry to have disappointed you.
Maaf karena aku mengecewakanmu.
It wasn't like I had to save the world or anything.
Aku tak harus selamatkan dunia.
All I had to do was call Obama.
Aku hanya perlu menelepon Obama.
But I even failed to do such a simple task.
Tapi tugas sederhana pun aku gagal.
If Obama finds out about this...
Jika Obama tahu ini...
Who in the world is Obama?
Siapa itu Obama?
Pardon?
Maaf?
He's not here.
Dia tak di sini.
I even went to the station office.
Aku bahkan ke kantor stasiun.
The workers told me that nothing peculiar happened.
Pegawai bilang tak ada yang aneh.
Are you happy now? You can close the hospital a little early today.
Kini kau senang?
I'm so tired. I need to go home and take a rest.
Aku lelah. Aku mau pulang dan istirahat.
He just uploaded something new on his Instagram.
Dia baru unggah foto baru di Instagram.
-Hey! -I think he's at Hangang Park.
- Hai! - Dia di Taman Hangang.
-I'll send it to you right away. -Don't send me anything.
Akan kukirimkan.
My gosh, this punk!
Astaga, si brengsek ini.
NURSE YU: PHOTO
PERAWAT YU
My gosh, I told him not to send me anything.
Astaga, aku melarangnya mengirimiku apa pun.
-Nurse Yu. -Did you know
- Perawat Yu. - Apa kau tahu
that Mr. Ma tried to commit suicide
Pak Ma mencoba bunuh diri
when he was getting treated at another hospital?
saat dirawat di rumah sakit lain?
What?
Apa?
That's why his family hesitated in hospitalizing him.
Itu sebabnya keluarganya ragu merawatnya di rumah sakit.
But...
Tapi kenapa...
Why are they telling us that now?
mereka bilang itu sekarang?
It must've been hard for the family to talk about it. What should we do?
Pasti sulit membicarakannya. Bagaimana ini?
Call the police and ask them to find him.
Hubungi polisi, minta mereka mencarinya.
He hates the police and firemen.
Dia benci polisi dan petugas damkar.
So you should...
Jadi, kau harus...
Nurse Yu!
Perawat Yu!
Yes?
Ya?
Call the police and wash your hands of this matter.
Hubungi polisi dan jangan ikut campur masalah ini.
Do you understand?
Kau mengerti?
Why is everyone giving me a hard time?
Kenapa semua memberiku kesulitan?
I'm not going to live like them.
Aku tak mau hidup seperti mereka.
NURSE YU
PERAWAT YU
What are you doing, and where are you?
Apa yang kau lakukan dan di mana kau?
I called the management office of Hangang Park.
Aku menelepon kantor Taman Hangang. Tak jauh dari sana.
My gosh, is he doing this for fun?
Astaga, apa dia melakukan ini untuk bersenang-senang?
-What? Obama? -Yes.
- Apa? Obama? - Ya.
Who is Obama? Why do you keep talking about him?
Siapa Obama? Kenapa kau terus membicarakannya?
Well, Obama was the 44th president of the United States.
Obama adalah Presiden Amerika Serikat ke-44.
He first ran for the presidency in 2008 as a Democrat.
Dia calon presiden tahun 2008 dari Partai Demokrat.
Pardon?
Apa?
But I know for sure that Obama can't save the world.
Tapi aku yakin Obama tak bisa selamatkan dunia.
What?
Apa?
My gosh, why does it have to be the Han River of all places?
Astaga, kenapa Sungai Han dari semua tempat?
My goodness. I don't know why I have to do this.
Astaga. Entah kenapa aku harus lakukan ini.
Why can't he save the world?
Kenapa dia tak bisa selamatkan dunia?
My gosh, it's true.
Astaga, benar.
Isn't it obvious?
Bukankah sudah jelas?
It really is that guy.
Sungguh pria itu.
-Then... -Why is he there?
- Lalu... - Mengapa dia di sana?
Then who can save the world?
Siapa yang bisa selamatkan dunia?
How am I supposed to know that?
Bagaimana aku tahu?
But I wouldn't have told you even if I did know
Tak akan kuberi tahu jika aku tahu
because I'm not interested in humans.
karena aku tak tertarik pada manusia.
My gosh!
Astaga.
Then why did TF 1004 call me and--
Lalu kenapa TF 1004 meneleponku dan…
Because he doesn't exist.
Karena dia tidak ada.
What do you mean?
Apa maksudmu?
There is not a single person
Tak ada seorang pun dengan nama seperti itu
in any of the three lands of gods.
di ketiga negeri dewa.
He doesn't exist.
Dia tidak ada.
Don't lie to me!
Jangan berbohong!
He shouldn't get too angry.
Dia tak boleh terlalu marah.
Stop lying to me, you swindler!
Jangan bohong, Penipu!
Listen to me carefully, you worthless human.
Dengarkan baik-baik, kau manusia tak berharga.
I am the next king of the Land of Water
Aku raja Negeri Air berikutnya
and the next emperor of deities.
dan kaisar dewa berikutnya.
I am Habaek, the God of Water.
Aku Habaek, Dewa Air.
But if you really are a god, you should know who can save the world.
Jika kau benar-benar dewa, kau tahu siapa yang bisa menyelamatkan dunia.
If it's not Obama, then who is it?
Jika bukan Obama, lalu siapa?
Listen to me carefully, you worthless human.
Dengarkan aku baik-baik, kau manusia tak berharga.
It takes just one person to ruin the world,
Hanya butuh satu orang untuk merusak dunia,
but it takes more than one person to save the world.
tapi lebih dari satu orang untuk selamatkan dunia.
So...
Jadi...
it's not something Obama can do by himself.
itu bukan sesuatu yang bisa dilakukan Obama sendiri.
But...
Tapi…
You should just focus on doing your best in life.
Kau harus fokus melakukan yang terbaik dalam hidup.
Don't waste time wandering around like this.
Jangan buang waktu seperti ini.
My gosh, that fool.
Si bodoh itu.
What more can I do?
Apa lagi yang bisa kulakukan?
What more can I do right now?
Apa lagi yang bisa kulakukan saat ini?
Regardless of how much I try, I still can't reach the sky.
Sekeras apa pun aku coba, aku belum bisa mencapai langit.
What more can I do?
Apa lagi yang bisa kulakukan?
I...
Aku...
I can't touch the sky.
Aku tak bisa menyentuh langit.
Mr. Ma Bong-yeol.
Pak Ma Bong-yeol.
What...
Apa...
What are you doing here?
Kenapa kau di sini?
Mr. Ma,
Pak Ma, kau bisa bicara padaku.
Talk to you about what? You don't even listen to what I say!
Bicara soal apa? Kau bahkan tak mendengarkan perkataanku!
About your story.
Kisahmu.
The story that you've always wanted to tell me.
Kisah yang selalu ingin kau sampaikan kepadaku.
I know that you wanted to show your father
Aku tahu kau ingin menunjukkan kepada ayahmu
that you could reach the sky.
kau bisa menjangkau langit.
That's why you tried hard to meet Obama. Let's talk about that story.
Karena itu kau berusaha bertemu Obama. Ayo kita bicarakan itu.
I already told you.
Aku sudah bilang.
I already told you everything,
Kuceritakan semuanya,
but you ignored me!
tapi kau mengabaikanku!
She tends to do that.
Dia biasa begitu.
-Mr. Ma, I-- -Don't come near me.
- Pak Ma, aku... - Jangan dekati aku.
I don't want to talk to you.
Aku tak mau bicara denganmu.
But Mr. Ma...
Tapi, Pak Ma...
Humans are so loud.
Manusia sangat berisik.
I should throw this away...
Aku harus buang ini...
-no matter what. -No. I don't need your help.
- Harus. - Tidak.
He's the only person who actually understands me.
Dia satu-satunya orang yang memahamiku.
Wait. Mr. Ma!
Tunggu. Pak Ma!
Stop right there!
Berhenti!
Mr. Ma...
Pak Ma...
Should I keep this and give it to Namsuri?
Aku simpan dan berikan ke Namsuri?
Please...
Kumohon...
Please stop him right now.
hentikan dia sekarang.
How dare a servant tell me what to do?
Berani-beraninya pelayan menyuruhku?
You do it.
Kau saja.
Mr. Ma.
Pak Ma.
Please come here. I'm sorry.
Tolong kemarilah. Maaf.
You were always like that while treating me.
Kau selalu seperti itu saat merawatku.
"Yes, I see. So?
"Ya, aku mengerti. Jadi?
I understand."
Aku mengerti."
What do you even understand?
Apa yang kau pahami?
Even now,
Bahkan sekarang,
you act like you care for me, but you have no intention of helping me.
kau bersikap seolah peduli, tapi kau tak berniat menolongku.
I'm sure you never even thought about...
Aku yakin kau tak pernah...
helping me while you sat behind that desk of yours.
mau membantuku saat kau duduk di belakang mejamu.
No.
Tidak.
I...
Aku...
14 YEARS AGO
14 TAHUN LALU
Dad.
Ayah.
Please.
Kumohon.
The person you are calling cannot answer your call.
Penerima tak bisa menjawab panggilan Anda.
Please leave a message after the beep.
Tinggalkan pesan setelah nada berikut.
I'm going to make you regret this for the rest of your life.
Aku akan membuatmu menyesal selama sisa hidupmu.
UNDYING CONNECTION BETWEEN PARENTS AND CHILDREN
HUBUNGAN ORANG TUA DAN ANAK SELAMANYA
Please. Please save me.
Kumohon.
Help me!
Tolong aku.
Please.
Kumohon.
Dad!
Ayah.
I regretted it.
Aku menyesalinya.
It was cold, dark,
Rasanya dingin, gelap...
lonely, and scary.
dan menakutkan.
But no one was there to help me.
Tapi tak ada yang membantuku.
What are you doing? I said I'm going to die right now!
Apa yang kau lakukan? Kubilang aku akan mati sekarang!
Do you think I'm lying?
Kau pikir aku berbohong?
Are you mocking me? Do you think I won't be able to do it?
Kau mengejekku? Kau pikir aku tidak berani?
Fine, I hope you all live a great life.
Baik, semoga kalian menjalani hidup yang hebat.
I hate this filthy world!
Aku benci dunia kotor ini!
No, no! Mr. Ma, stop!
Tidak! Pak Ma, hentikan!
-Help! -No.
- Tolong! - Tidak.
No!
Tidak.
-Help! -No.
- Tolong! - Tidak.
Mr. Ma!
Pak Ma.
Dr. Yun, help!
Dokter Yun, tolong!
Please.
Kumohon.
Please save me!
Tolong selamatkan aku.
Dad!
Ayah.
No, please...
Tidak, kumohon…
No!
Tidak.
Help!
Tolong!
No!
Tidak!
You're one reckless woman.
Kau wanita yang ceroboh.
Hold this.
Pegang ini.
You guys are so loud.
Kalian berisik sekali.
I want all of you to leave my house.
Aku ingin kalian tinggalkan rumahku.
I didn't want to go in because it's so dirty.
Aku tak mau masuk karena kotor.
No!
Tidak!
My gosh, no! Please come out.
Hentikan! Kumohon keluarlah.
Get out of the water!
Keluarlah dari air.
Please get out of the water. Please.
Tolong keluarlah dari air. Kumohon.
Gosh, I'm sorry.
Astaga, maafkan aku.
I'm sorry.
Maaf.
I apologize for everything.
Aku minta maaf untuk segalanya.
I told you to be quiet.
Aku menyuruhmu diam.
My gosh. Mr. Ma!
Astaga. Pak Ma.
Mr. Ma. Please...
Pak Ma. Kumohon...
Please.
Tolonglah.
Stop it!
Hentikan!
My lips belong to TF 1004.
Bibirku milik TF 1004.
I'm sorry.
Maaf.
And thank you.
Dan terima kasih.
I'm glad you're thankful.
Aku senang kau berterima kasih.
Take that fool away from here.
Bawa pergi si bodoh itu.
Hey!
Hai!
I told you to hold this!
Sudah kubilang pegang ini!
It's not...
Bukan...
because I wanted to eat this.
karena aku ingin makan ini.
I was just saving it for Namsuri.
Aku menyimpannya untuk Namsuri.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Fate.
Takdir.
It must be fate.
Ini pasti takdir.
Are you really a god?
Apa kau dewa sungguhan?
Habaek is here.
Habaek ada di sini.
I've been thinking about you.
Aku memikirkanmu.
Shut up.
Diam.
Nothing could get you off my mind.
Tak ada yang bisa membuatmu melupakanku.
I must be going crazy.
Aku pasti gila.
Look who's here. A beggar.
Lihat siapa yang datang. Pengemis.
Why are you following my woman around and bothering her?
Kenapa menguntit wanitaku dan mengganggunya?
Were you playing the knight in shining armor?
Apa kau kesatria berzirah?
I keep running into this girl, Yun So-a.
Aku terus bertemu Yun So-a.
Shall we switch over to a mystery, thriller, and suspense movie?
Haruskah beralih ke film misteri, thriller, dan ketegangan?
You and I are accomplices with regard to the sacred stone.
Kau dan aku bersekongkol dalam hal batu suci.
Were you toying with me? You foolish human.
Apa kau mempermainkanku? Manusia bodoh.
Don't you dare test me.
Jangan coba-coba mengetesku.
EPILOGUE
EPILOG
-High Priest. -Gosh, you brat.
- Pendeta Agung. - Astaga, Nak.
Wait, High Priest.
Tunggu, Pendeta Agung.
High Priest.
Pendeta Agung.
What is fate? Please tell me.
Apa itu takdir? Tolong katakan.
-I won't tell you. -High Priest, please.
- Aku tak akan memberitahumu. - Pendeta Agung, kumohon.
High Priest, what is fate? Please tell me.
Pendeta Agung, apa itu takdir? Tolong katakan.
Disclosing the profound secret.
Mengungkapkan rahasia besar.